hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so now we are going to talk
about a scenario where uh we have to
download a particular file and maybe we
have to perform some other things on
that like maybe verifying a PDF file or
verifying a image file or any particular
file from your application right so this
is the
scenario now there are two ways of doing
this either uh you can go ahead with the
normal way of downloading a file which
is when you click on that file then it
downloads it into the downloads folder
from there uh you can then uh transfer
it into a separate folder or you can go
ahead and verify in the downloads folder
right um but this might be a lengthy
process and sometimes it may be a little
complicated there's a more easy way of
uh getting this done uh using the curl
command and uh you can use the Cur
command in tosa as well okay so let me
show you how you can do that now for
this U I picked up um a sample
application which has got a number of
different download links you can can see
here right so these uh all these
download links we have to uh download
this file maybe sample media.
file.png okay and then uh we can also
verify whether this file exists or
not so um this is the scenario now how
you can do that um as I said the usual
way is to click on that and then it
downloads and then you can go to the
downloads folder but there is the other
way um and that is using curl okay what
is curl um it is a open source Tool uh
it is a command line tool uh to transfer
data using different uh Network
protocols okay so uh the name stands for
client for URL and that is called curl
right you can download it for free um
for Windows uh operating system right
from here and uh it will get installed
into your command line tool
okay uh once it's downloaded uh you can
go to uh
CMD and here you can check whether it is
downloaded or not okay so just type c
and then
help if it returns all this options that
means uh it is installed on your system
and uh you can use it now um we are
going to use one of the parameters here
which is this output parameter and uh in
this output parameter it will download
the file into this particular file
location which we specify okay and there
are other options also here so let's
pick up an example okay so here uh if I
come here and I can pick up some link I
will copy the link address here and then
come back here so here I'm going to type
curl and then uh we need to put the link
here of that particular file
and then we have to type the parameter d
o and then uh we can type the file path
here okay so if I want to download it
into a specific folder like this CM
folder so I'm going to specify this
followed by this file name so I'm going
to keep it
spectrum.png
okay and then uh you will see that it
has completed a download I can verify
that going to my CM folder you will see
spectrum.png is downloaded right so uh
that's the way uh how you can download a
particular file directly from your
command line tool now uh we are going to
do the same thing uh with tosa Okay so
let's go to test cases and let's create
a folder here we are going to call this
download
and then I am going
to add a test case called download
file okay and then we need to add a test
step here which is called the tbox Start
program so here uh we are going to start
a program with some arguments and that
program is the powershell.exe okay
so we were going to execute this command
in Powershell so I will start this and
then um in the arguments the first
argument would be
Cur okay and then um we'll follow the
same way how we have done it earlier
this time let's pick up a different um
file which we want to download I am
copying the link address here and then
come back here I am going going to pass
this link here then the third argument
is- o That's the uh parameter and then
uh we are going to pass uh where we want
to download it right so again I'm going
to download it in cm
file and I am going to specify the file
name
media.png okay so these are all the
arguments also in wait for exit I will
specify true here so it will wait for
exiting the
application and then let's go ahead and
let's execute
this okay so I'm going to execute this
test case
now and you will see here um it executed
the powershell.exe with this arguments
and then process stopped so how to
verify whether it was downloaded well
you can go back to the temp folder the
media.png is saved
here now coming to the next step uh
which is to verify whether the file
exists um not manually but through tosa
so that can be done easily by adding
another test step and here you can check
for file
existence so tbox file existence that's
the
module and here I just need to pass the
directory where that file exists and I
need to pass the file name here
okay um and then the action mode will be
verify now uh if I go ahead and just run
this
okay so you will see uh verification was
successful and expected value found one
match for this particular file okay so
this is how it works uh you can use the
curl command uh to download any
particular file uh you can use the
powershell.exe or the command line tool
for Windows and then uh you can perform
uh the verification whether that file
exists or not okay so end to end
scenario where uh you can download the
file and then you can also verify the
file that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next video